Finding Aid for Frank Angelo (1914- ), Papers 1941-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical file
  - Kansas State University-Seminar March 1973 (Box 11)
  - Kent State (Box 11)
  - Lansing (Box 11)
  - Leadership Detroit (Box 11)
  - Leonard, Robert F (Box 11)
  - Mayor's Community Cultural Council (Box 11)
  - Mercy College Board (Box 11)
  - Mercy College student publications, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Michigan Daily Newspapers (Box 11)
  - Michigan Welfare Study Commission (Box 11)
  - New Detroit, Inc., 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Newspapers Fund, Inc. 1960-1970 (Box 11)
  - Operation LINC (Box 11)
  - Pentagon briefings (Box 11)
  - Peoples of Detroit Project (Box 11)
  - Police Athletic League (PAL) (Box 11)
  - Prismatic Club (Box 11)
  - Race crisis-Press coverage (Box 11)
  - Racial (Box 11)
  - Riot-1967
    - Article (Box 11)
    - Detroit Urban League Survey (Box 11)
    - Meyer Survey (Box 11)
    - The News Media and the Riots (Box 11)
    - Reporting (Box 11)
    - Riot Speech materials (Box 11)
    - Miscellanea (Box 11)
  - Reader Insurance (Box 11)
  - Recruiting (Box 11)
  - Report on Methods being used by Managing Editors to reduce costs in the newsroom (Box 11)
  - Research-Comics (Box 11)
  - Romney, George (Box 11)
  - Schools (Box 11)
  - Simons, Leonard N (Box 11)
  - Southfield Housing Proposal (Box 11)
  - Stadium Task Force (Box 11)
  - Traffic Safety Task Force (Box 12)
  - United Community Services (Box 12)
  - United Foundation
    - Geographical Expansion Committee (Box 12)
    - Summary Report of the Priorities Subcommittee to the Special Study Committee (Box 12)
  - University Cultural Center Association, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - University of Detroit Seminar (Box 12)
  - University of Michigan Panel (Box 12)
  - Using the Newspaper in the Classroom Program
    - Papers, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Teacher's manual (Box 12)
  - Vietnam, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - WQRS (Box 12)
  - Wayne State University
    - Fund, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - History (Box 12)
    - Panel (Box 12)
    - Proposal for creation of a research institute (Box 12)
    - Teaching (Box 12)
  - Williams, Roberta (Box 12)
  - Youth Opportunity Council (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 12)
- Education and Teaching
  The Education and Teaching series consists of files on college courses Angelo taught, including one at the University of Michigan titled "The Other Detroit", consulting activities for Michigan State and Wayne State and a file on the Detroit Cooley High Parents Club
  - Cooley High School Parents Club 1968-1971 (Box 14)
  - Michigan State University
    - Consultant Committee 1970 (Box 14)
    - Highway Traffic Safety Center Advisory Committee 1971 (Box 14)
  - University-City Consortium, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - University of Michigan course--"The Other Detroit." 1976
    - Class roster (Box 14)
    - Correspondence (Box 14)
    - Information for course (Box 14)
    - Lesson plans (Box 14)
  - Wayne State University
    - Weekend College
      - General information (Box 14)
      - Report--"To Educate the People" (with Otto Feinstein) (Box 14)
- Miscellaneous (Box 14)
- Visual materials (Box 15)
  The visual materials series includes personal photographs of Angelo and his family and also copyprints of photographs collected by Angelo to be used in his various writings about Michigan and Detroit. There are also a few original photographs given to Angelo. Of most interest here are images of radio and television broadcasts of "The Lone Ranger" radio program and a television cooking program originating from Detroit.
  - Photographs, Personal
    - Angelo at various meetings (Box 15)
    - Angelo receiving awards, speaking, etc (Box 15)
    - Angelo, Betty (Box 15)
    - Family (Box 15)
    - Groups, including Frank Angelo (Box 15)
    - Portraits (Box 15)
    - Vietnam, Felix Greene photos (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, not Frank Angelo (Box 15)
  - Photographs (mainly copyprints collected for use in various writings about Detroit and Michigan)
    - Automobiles and related (Box 15)
    - Battle Creek Enquirer (Box 15)
    - Business establishments (Box 15)
    - Celebrations, parades, and other demonstrations (Box 15)
    - Chrysler Corporation (Box 15)
    - Depression (Box 15)
    - Detroit Institute of Art (Box 15)
    - Detroit Public Schools (Box 15)
    - Detroit views (Box 15)
    - Detroit and Michigan Miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Interurbans (Box 15)
    - Lone Ranger; radio; miscellaneous Dick Osgood photos (Box 15)
    - Lumbering (Box 15)
    - Old News Boys (Box 15)
    - Penobscot Building (Box 15)
    - Political and other public personalities (Box 15)
    - Sanders Company (Box 15)
    - South Haven views (Box 15)
    - Spina (Tony) photos (Box 15)
    - Upper Peninsula (mainly Sault Ste. Marie and Houghton, Michigan) (Box 15)
    - Vernor's Company (Box 15)
  - Videotape
    - Tribute to Judd Arnett September 22, 1983 a benefit for Cleary College, hosted by Sonny Eliot, with featured speakers Judd Arnett, Gilbert Bursley, Frank Angelo, Richard Chrysler, J.P. McCarthy, Tom Kizer, William McLean, Jerry Rideout, Neal Shine, and G. Mennen Williams, VHS videocassette, poor picture and sound quality (Box 15)
- Writing
  The Writing series includes materials which document Angelo's writing during and after his stint at the Detroit Free Press. In this series, there is a folder of columns (approximately 90% from 1979) Angelo wrote while he was at the Detroit Free Press, drafts of columns, editing projects he worked on, and speeches. Many of the materials in these files contain notations, corrections, and remarks written by Angelo with his distinctive felt tip pen. This series also has folders with materials from Angelo's other writing projects including the entry he wrote for "Detroit" in the Encyclopedia Britannica and the From Bloomfield to Birmingham book. The largest subseries is the materials relating to Yesterday's Detroit. This subseries contains chapter drafts with corrections and correspondence, research and photo agreements, reviews, correspondence with Seeman Publishing, and reviews. The correspondence with Seeman Publishing documents Angelo's decision to write the book through the editing process and final publication of the book.
  - Book: On Guard, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Magazine Articles
    - "Detroit zwichen Krise und Expansion" (Box 13)
    - "It's Time to Listen, At Last, to the soft, Unheard Voices," 1967 (Box 13)
    - "But Don't Lose Sight of Our Traditions," 1975 (Box 13)
  - Affirmative action consulting 1988-1989 (Box 16)
  - Detroit Free Press Columns, (bulk of columns, 1979), 1977-1979 (Box 16)
  - Drafts of columns and miscellaneous writings 1970s-1990s (Box 16)
  - Editing Projects 1988-1990 (Box 16)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica 1974 (Box 16)
  - From Bloomfield to Birmingham 1989 (Box 16)
  - Speeches 1970-1990s, 16 folders (Box 16)
  - Publishing agreements 1988-1992 (Box 16)
  - Yesterday's Detroit, 1973-1976
    - Drafts with corrections/correspondence (Box 16)
    - Research/photo agreements (Box 16)
    - Reviews/promotional material (Box 16)
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
      - Seeman Publishing
        - General (Box 16)
        - Initial proofs (Box 16)
        - Royalties (Box 16)
      - Reviews